Guide to the Elmer S. Phillips papers, [ca. 1943-1994]
Phillips, Elmer S. papers, [ca. 1943-1994]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Elmer S. Phillips papers, ca.1943-1994
21-42-3218
Phillips, E. S.
2.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, lecture notes, publications, photographs, slides, films, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, lecture notes, publications, photographs, slides, and other papers of a Communications professor. Includes photographs of the 1937 Ithaca flood, aerial views of Cornell (1937) and movie films taken by Phillips, including Cornell University scenes, faculty members, academic activities, sports, campus events and agrciultural activities at Cornell. Includes silent black and white film, silent color film, and sound color film and copies of the American Wine Society Journal and the Tompkins County Hospital newsletter, Hospital Highlights.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Elmer S. Phillips is Professor Emeritus of Communications in the New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, lecture notes, publications, photographs, slides, and other papers of a Communications professor. Includes photographs of the 1937 Ithaca flood, aerial views of Cornell (1937) and movie films taken by Phillips, including Cornell University scenes, faculty members, academic activities, sports, campus events and agricultural activities at Cornell. Includes silent black and white film, silent color film, and sound color film and copies of the American Wine Society Journal and the Tompkins County Hospital newsletter, Hospital Highlights.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Phillips, E. S.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences--Faculty.; Cornell University--Athletics.; Cornell University--Buildings.; Cornell University--Description Views.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Students.
Titles:
Hospital Highlights.; American Wine Society Journal.
Subjects:
Communication--Study and teaching.; Floods--New York (State)--Ithaca.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Motion pictures (visual works).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
The films Helen Powell Smith and Railway Exhibit - Farm and Home Special from this collection have been digitized and can be found on Cornell's Library Media Space website along with other Home Economics and related films.
CONTAINER LIST
- 1935 Flood Photos, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Aerial Photos of Cornell 1937, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Radio Tower, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1937 Flood Photos, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3A)
- National Scouting Conference, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 3B)
- Script for the Movie "Roots of Empire", 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Contact People for the movie; dates and places the movie was shot; correspondence about the movie
- "Roots of Empire" Teachers Guide and Correspondence City of Ithaca meetings Hospital Highlights Vol. 1 No. 1 1979 - Vol. 3 No. 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- American Wine Society Newsletter, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Slides of Cornell, 1962-1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Publications started by Phillips while in Costa Rica, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Visual Aids in Agricultural Extension" (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Photograph - Radio Workshop in Turrialba, Costa Rica, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Elmer Phillips lectures on Film "Fifty Golden Years" Hotel School, 1968-1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Elmer Phillips Epsilon Sigma Phi Correspondence, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Hospital Highlights, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Hospital Highlights, 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Elmer Phillips notes on photography/Hospital Highlights, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- E Phillips Photo Enhancement of ERTS Imagery (2 nice packets) / "Land use Classification with Simulated Satellite Photography" packet, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Investigators for Agriculture, Forestry /ERTS Evaluation for land use inventory, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Elmer Phillips Notes on Film, 1952-1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Life Style comments, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- "Roots of Empire" info/ "Life" October 4, 1937 - Cornell picture, 1937/1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Aerial Photos of Cornell (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Exhibit photos/ Poultry periodicals/ Teaching guides, 1942-1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Wine making/ Photography notes, 1966-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Elmer Phillips lectures, 1957-1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- "Skylab EREP Investigations Summary", 1978 (Box 2, Volume 1)
- Enhancement and Evaluation of Skylab Photography for Potential Land use inventories, 1975 (Box 2, Volume 2)
- Slides, negatives, correspondence, 1936-1970 (Box 3, Volume 1)
- Reunion at Hoy Field,(Commercial Kodachrome), 1952 (Box 4, Reel 1)
- Professor Randolph Botany,(Commercial Kodachrome), 1950 (Box 4, Reel 2)
- Lev Saltonstall Botany,(Commercial Kodachrome), 1952 (Box 4, Reel 3)
- Whiteface Mountain/ Sandy Atwood Botany,(Commercial Kodachrome), 1951 (Box 4, Reel 4)
- Farm and Home Week Event-Judging pavilion; students preparing Holsteins for the ring; Tractor-drawn tree mover; Inside the judging pavilion (Commercial Kodachrome), 1952 (Box 4, Reel 5)
- Farm and Home Week Event-Crowd coming from Bailey Hall after a Farm and Home Week Lecture (Commercial Kodachrome), 1952 (Box 4, Reel 6)
- Crew team shots, (Commercial Kodachrome), 1952 (Box 4, Reel 7)
- Photos of elms in different parts of New York,(Commercial Kodachrome), 1952 (Box 4, Reel 8)
- Tree-removal, (Commercial Kodachrome), 1952 (Box 4, Reel 9)
- Cornell Campus shots,(Commercial Kodachrome), 1952 (Box 4, Reel 10)
- ROTC review,(Commercial Kodachrome), 1952 (Box 4, Reel 11)
- Skiing Tar Young Hill,(Commercial Kodachrome), 1952 (Box 4, Reel 12)
- Spring Day,(Commercial Kodachrome), 1952 (Box 4, Reel 13)
- Floats on Spring Day,(Commercial Kodachrome), 1952 (Box 4, Reel 14)
- Professor C B Raymond with corn, (Commercial Kodachrome), 1951 (Box 4, Reel 15)
- Professor Raymond and Pratt taking soil samples,(Commercial Kodachrome), 1952 (Box 4, Reel 16)
- Carnival (Commercial Kodachrome) (Box 4, Reel 17)
- Professor Helen Smith - Home Economics (Commercial Kodachrome). (Use copy DVD-995 in the same box.), F-823 (Box 4, Reel 18)
  Click here to see a digitized version of the film.
  Screen test of Helen Powell Smith narrating to the camera (without sound).
- Professor Helen Smith Home Economics - copy of F-823, DVD-995 (Box 4)
- Container with four untitled reels (Box 4, Reel 19)
- Biological Control of Oriental Fruit Moth #1 (Box 5, Reel 1)
- Biological Control of Oriental Fruit Moth #2 (Box 5, Reel 2)
- Caponizing (Box 5, Reel 3)
- Celery Harvesting Methods #1 (Box 5, Reel 4)
- Celery Harvesting Methods #2 (Box 5, Reel 5)
- Garden Preparation (Box 5, Reel 6)
- Japanese Beetle #1 (Box 5, Reel 7)
- Japanese Beetle #2 (Box 5, Reel 8)
- Maple Sap into Maple Syrup #1 (Box 5, Reel 9)
- Maple Sap into Maple Syrup #2 (Box 5, Reel 10)
- Railway Exhibit - Farm and Home Special. (Use DVD-994 in same box.), 1946; F-822 (Box 5, Reel 11)
  A 4-H farming and home economics practices exhibit on-board a New York Central train.
- Railway Exhibit- Farm and Home Special. Copy of Film F-822, 1946; DVD-994 (Box 5)
- Steps Take Time in Feeding the Hens #1 (Box 5, Reel 12)
- Steps Take Time in Feeding the Hens #2 (Box 5, Reel 13)
- Steps Take Time in Watering Hens (Box 5, Reel 14)
- Steps Take Time in Gathering and Packing Eggs #1 (Box 5, Reel 15)
- Steps Take Time in Gathering and Packing Eggs #2 (Box 5, Reel 16)
- Transplanting Shrubs, Evergreens and Trees #1 (Box 5, Reel 17)
- Transplanting Shrubs, Evergreens and Trees #2 (Box 5, Reel 18)